Haoyang Liu (Vincent)

Software Engineer

Contact

(949) 383-0000 · San Jose, CA haoyang.liu@sjsu.com github.com/lhy2016 linkedin.com/in/haoyang-liu-39156a164 haoyangliu.com

Objective

Seeking a software engineer position, bringing professionalism from 2 years of full-stack experience and an MS Software Engineering degree. Familiar with modern web tech stacks and best practices. A cooperative person with good communication skills and willing to accept new challenges.

Language

Java, Python, PHP, Javascript, CSS, SQL, HTML, XML

Tools and Standards

Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Flask, Django, Node.js, Bootstrap, SASS, React.js, Angular.js, AJAX, JSON, WebSocket, Docker, Nginx, CDN, AWS EC2, CloudWatch, Android, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST, MVC, HTTP, SMTP, TCP/IP

Education

M.S. in Software Engineering, San Jose State University B.S. in Software Engineering, San Jose State University 2020 - 2022, GPA: 3.7

2015 - 2018

Work Experience

Learn Education, Independent Off-sourcing Developer, Remote

Feb 2020 - Aug 2020

- Developed an education website independently including video courses, news, blog, forum sections, admin management, and logging system using HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, PHP, and MySQL (http://otp.whv.mybluehost.me/)
- Managed development life cycles with Agile methodologies and communicated with party A to achieve delivery

DocSpot, Full-Stack Developer, San Jose, CA

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

- Developed an internal-use web crawler, Fetch, in Java integrating Chrome Devtools Protocol and Headless Chromium; made it successfully collect 10M core business data records over 800+ websites quarterly
- Developed a data analyzing program using **Java** and **MySQL** independently; designed and implemented complicated SQL queries statements, which helped *Fetch* filtered out 90% of non-relevant links to hospital or clinic
- Developed a tracking system for *Fetch* by serializing its operations and storing them in the database in **Java**, **JSON**, and **MySQL**, which made *Fetch* restorable from the previous run; improved its usability and efficiency by at most 70%
- Developed a core map service used on production; implemented MVC and rendering changes using **Javascript** and **AJAX**; the service brought 20% potential users and completely save the budget of using other map services
- Designed and developed provider's card view for **SEO** purposes in **Spring MVC**, which would be indexed by the Google search results as sitelinks; applied data visualization using **Javascript chart library**(Apex Chart) to draw potential interest

Internship Experience

CTI One Corporation, Software Engineer Intern, Santa Clara, CA

Sep 2017 - Feb 2018

- Implemented image augmentation for machine learning preprocessing purpose using rotation and Gaussian blur in OpenCV
 Python, which improved the preparation efficiency by 70%
- Conducted **performance testing** by adding round trip timestamp between different code blocks; detected the IO problem and completely removed latency; increased the overall run-time efficiency by 60%
- Corrected lane detection and turning logic with OpenCV, which made the autonomous vehicle successfully following the lane

DHTHX Tech. Co., Ltd, Software Engineer Intern, Dalian, China

May 2017 - Aug 2017

 Built enterprise product management desktop app using C#.NET interfacing Oracle database; successfully learned basic C#.NET development and basic database CRUD operations

Projects Experience

HomeFinder, homefinder.haoyangliu.com

 Developed a real estate website that users can search, rent, buy, or list properties using React.js, Python Flask, Flickr CDN, and MySQL; deployed on GCP with Docker and added Nginx as a proxy server and load balancer

- Added message queue(Kafka) between property posting(server-side) and image uploading(Flickr API) services
- Managed the team and development process using **Agile** methodologies as a scrum master; held weekly scrum meetings, recorded progress with burn-down chart, organized backlog items, assigned tasks, and conducted retrospective meetings

Personal Website, haoyangliu.com

- Developed personal portfolio site with **HTML**, **CSS**, **Javascript** and **PHP** integrating **Mailgun** for email sending service; developed a very challenging tic tac toe bot using **Javascript**
- Deployed on GCP with Docker and added Nginx as a proxy server; configured wildcard SSL with letsEncrypt on Docker

Job Scraper

• Designed and developed a job searching automation tool for personal use using **Python Selenium**; encapsulates common web-browsing behaviors and parses input **XML** files to support multiple sites

Invest Assistant

- Developed a web app using **Flask** that assists users to make smart investment decisions on stocks and ETFs; developed a service that caches **Yahoo Finance(yfinance)** data and regularly updates local data to greatly reduce the delay of API query
- Used ThreadPoolExecutor to make the data service and web app backend run in parallel